考虑下证人保护计划
Think about Witness Protection.
爸爸  我们应该多搞这样的活动
Dad, we should do this way more often.
无论我在哪里  我的一部分都和你在一起
Wherever I go, part of me is with you.
我想我做不到
I don't think I can do this.
我必须得走了
I have to go.
这是保证我们全家安全的唯一途径
It's the only way to keep our family safe.
举起手  不要动
Hands up! Don't move.
你把我给吓死了
You scared the bejesus out of me.
我的天  发生什么了
Oh, my God. What happened?
爱瑞丝出事了
It's Iris.
闪 电 侠
第六季
第十八集
沃利提醒过我爱瑞丝有些不对劲
Wally warned me that something was off with Iris.
然后烈日袭击了冰霜
And then Sunshine attacked Frost.
我注意到了她对你有些奇怪
I noticed that she was being weird with you,
甚至有些冷漠
cold even.
但我什么都没说
I just didn't say anything.
-这不是你的错  -我感觉是这样的
- It's not your fault. - Well, it feels like it.
那其他的复制品现在何处
Well, where are the other duplicates now?
爱瑞丝的复制品已经消失了
Iris' copy is gone.
她
She...
那东西
It...
在我眼前碎成了无数的碎片
shattered into a million pieces right in front of me.
我知道那并不是她
I know it wasn't her,
但就在那一切发生之前  她就像是
but right before it happened, she seemed so...
活生生的
alive.
几乎就像爱瑞丝真的回来了
Almost like she was really back.
我一直在给自己希望  这一切都会解决
I'm trying to have hope that it's all gonna work out,
但我还是不禁地感觉到
but I can't help feeling...
乔  如果这次我救不了她怎么办
Joe, what if I can't save her this time?
我相信你能救她的
And I believe that you can,
但你相信自己吗
but do you?
他们就那么消失了吗
They're just gone?
"镜像宇宙"到底是什么意思
What does that even mean-- "Mirrorverse"?
-我们还能把他们找回来吗  -我的天
- Can we even get them back? - Oh, my God.
我们  我们得警告大卫的丈夫
We--we have to warn David's husband.
我一直和卡米拉的复制品生活在一起
I've been living with some copy of Kamilla
而真正的她被困在了某个地方吗
while the real one's trapped somewhere?
伊娃说他们现在暂时安全
Eva said they're safe for now.
你就相信她的话了吗
And you're taking her word for it?
我们现在根本不知道他们是否已经死了
For all we know, they're dead already.
他们没死  别
They're not, so just--
别往那想
you don't even think about that.
我们不得不考虑那种可能
We have to think about that.
如果创造卡米拉的复制品这个过程
What if creating Kamilla's duplicate
杀掉了真正的卡米拉怎么办
actually killed the real Kamilla?
辛格也是  爱瑞丝也是
Same thing with Singh, same thing with Iris.
-说话呀  -你想让我说什么
- Hello? - What do you want me to say?
说什么都行  说我们有计划  会救他们回来
Anything, that we have a plan, that we'll get them back.
我没有计划  西斯科
I don't have a plan, Cisco.
伊娃能在一眨眼间通过任何一面镜子
Eva can move anywhere through any mirror
穿越到宇宙的任何地方
in the universe in the blink of an eye.
她比我快
She's faster than I am,
而我却应该阻止她
and somehow, I'm supposed to stop her
同时仍然祈祷爱瑞丝和其他人
and still hope to God that Iris and everybody else
仍然活在一个我们都不理解的世界里吗
is still alive in a world that we don't even understand?
你俩都没错 好吗  你俩说的都对
You're both right, okay? You're both right.
但我们不能分崩离析
But we cannot fall apart.
我们需要解决问题  而不是互相指责
We need to work the problem, not tear each other down.
所以我会这么做
So here's what I'm gonna do--
我会打电话给大卫的丈夫
I am gonna call David's husband,
问问他是否见到了辛格的复制品
and I am gonna see if he has seen Singh's duplicate.
我去搜查宾利大楼
I'll check the Bentley Building.
镜像爱瑞丝和卡米拉经常单独在那里
Mirror-Iris and Kamilla were alone there a lot.
也许她们留下了什么踪迹
Maybe they left something behind.
-很好  -要我陪你去吗
- Good. - You want company?
也许你应该找些别的事情做
Maybe you should find something else to do.
你和我一起吧
You can come with me.
我看能不能挖出些
I'm gonna see if I can dig up any details
这个伊娃·麦克洛奇的料
on this Eva McCulloch.
如果镜像宇宙只不过是另一个维度
If the Mirrorverse is just another dimension,
也许能够通过振动的方式进入其中
there might be a way to enter vibrationally.
凯特琳还在康复中  所以我不能叫她帮忙
Caitlin's still on the mend, so I can't ask her for help.
就是说我只能靠自己了
I guess that means I'm doing this one on my own.
巴里  我明白你的感受
Barry, look, I understand how you're feeling--
塞西尔  我知道你想帮我
Cecile, I know you're trying to help me, and...
我很感激  但是...
I appreciate it, but...
现在我要研究人造神速力
right now I'm gonna work on the Artificial Speed Force.
我只是...  如果我没有能力与伊娃抗衡
I just-- there's no point in finding Eva
找到她也没有用
if I'm useless against her.
我看过伊娃的机密文件
I read Eva's secret files,
现在我知道有一个卡米拉的镜像
and now I know that there's a mirror version of Kamilla,
就是说真正的卡米拉肯定在这里某个地方
which means that the real Kamilla must be in here somewhere.
我要找到她
I have to find her.
我没法思考
I can't think straight.
伊娃把这叫做神经失调
Eva calls it "Neural dissonance,"
人的思维方式在这里会改变
the way that your mind changes here.
我录下这段视频给你看
I'm leaving this here for you in case you find it,
但是别找我
but don't find me.
巴里
Barry...
无论世界要怎么将我们分开
No matter what worlds try to keep us apart,
我永远都会找到你的
I will always be with you.
我是有多蠢
How dumb am I?
我也有同感
Yeah, that feeling's going around.
我一直和复制人共事了这么长时间
I've been working side by side with duplicates this whole time.
我真是个菜鸟记者
Some budding reporter I am.
等等  《公民报》现在归我管了吗
Wait, does that mean I'm in charge of "The Citizen"?
我要怎么...
How the hell am I supposed to--
神速
Godspeed.
阻止其他极速者的人就是你吗
You're the one that stopped the others.
看来也不怎么样
I'm not impressed.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
谢谢
Thank you.
我正想找个理由测试一下这个脉冲加农炮
I was looking for a reason to test out this pulse cannon.
我们走着瞧
This isn't over.
你不是说四个神速
Didn't you say all four Godspeeds
都关在铁山监狱里吗
were locked up at Iron Heights?
这些只是有声音的生物无人机
Those are just cybernetic drones with modem-speak.
这一个会说话
This one was talking.
话说  你们这个地方
And by the way, do you not happen to have
没有保护措施的吗
protective protocols for this place?
别把责任算在我头上
Do not put this on me.
我正在想办法进入镜像宇宙
I am trying to figure out a way into the Mirrorverse.
-你在做什么呢  -我拯救了我们的极速者
- What were you doing? - I was saving our speedster.
好样的  你做了点事
Good for you. You did something.
谢谢  我能炫耀一下吗
Thank you. Could I have a parade?
你好像什么都没做
You don't seem to be doing anything else.
-别吵了  消停一下  -什么
- Stop! Just give it a-- - What?
-你在想什么  -我...
- What are you thinking? - I...
西斯科  你是科学狂人
Cisco, you're the schmience-y guy.
你肯定有计划吧
You must have some kind of a plan, right?
西斯科  你在听我说话吗
Cisco, you still-- still with us, bud, or--
拉尔夫  别吵  我正在尽力救我们的朋友
Ralph, please, I'm trying to get our friends back right now.
好  好
Okay, okay.
阿莱格拉  你说过神速的闪电
Allegra, you said Godspeed's lightning
引起了爆炸
caused some sort of blast.
他就像是在屋里掀起了闪电风暴
Yeah, he was like a frickin' lightning storm in the room,
但是真正造成破坏的是他的雷暴
but it was his thunder that did the damage.
不是雷暴  是振动
Not thunder-- vibrations.
符合逻辑
Makes sense.
如果速度够快  就能产生音爆
If you go fast enough, you create a sonic boom.
终极速度转化为空气中的振动
Velocity transmutes into vibrations in the air,
只是这个神速想到了办法...
only this Godspeed figured out a way...
逆转这些振动
To reverse those vibrations
并加利用  从极速者身上吸取速度
and use them to extract speed from a speedster.
所以他渴求力量  我们要怎么阻止他
Okay, so he's power hungry. How do we stop him?
我们要对振动音速
Well, we'd need a really, really deep understanding
做一个深入透彻的了解
of vibrational sonics.
好极了  我们有吗
Great. Do we have that?
-没有  -我知道有人能帮我们
- Not really, no. - I know who could help us.
哈特利  哈特利·拉瑟威
Hartley. Hartley Rathaway.
哈特利·拉瑟威是谁
Who's Hartley Rathaway?
他是个精通
He is an expert
心理声学与声振动的专家
in psychoacoustics and sonic vibrations.
他以前为尖端科研实验室工作
He used to work for S.T.A.R. Labs.
并且  他还是个混球  恨你入骨
Also, a jerk who hates us so much
想要把你内脏切成丝
he tried to julienne your insides.
结果是他在危机之后
It turns out that he hates The Flash
更加恨闪电侠了  我们不知道具体原因
even more post-Crisis, only we don't really know why.
纠正  我知道为什么
Correction--I know why.
我的危机研究找到了问题的答案
My Crisis research dug up the answer to that.
闪电侠击败吹笛人与他的手下
手下  不对  那时只有我和哈特利
Henchmen? No, it was only me and Hartley.
这个时间线上不是
Not in this timeline.
吹笛人的快乐同伙们想要趁着你
Pied Piper's Band of Merry Men tried to flank you
在用车玩音乐的时候夹击你
while you were distracted playing musical cars.
是  你看到了他们
Yeah, you clocked them,
但是当他们中的一个向你射击时
but when one of them tried to shoot at you,
你用闪电回击
you countered with a lightning bolt.
那闪电与武器相冲  然后...
That lightning collided with the weapon's blast, and...
结果那个人是哈特利的心腹
Turns out, that was Hartley's right-hand man...
罗德里克·史密斯
Roderick Smith.
是寒霜
It's Frost.
抱歉各位  我得处理一下这事
Sorry, guys, I got to-I got to check on this.
罗德里克·史密斯被关押在水星实验室的
Roderick Smith is being held in an energy containment unit
能量封锁装置中
in Mercury Labs.
显然  这是唯一能
Apparently, it's the only thing
阻止他完全瓦解的办法
that's keeping him from completely disintegrating.
我想吹笛人是不会帮忙了
I guess that's a no to Pied Piper's help.
他确实差点杀死我们  所以
Well, he did almost kill us, so...
咱别为了谁杀谁吵架
Let's not bicker over who killed who.
我们可以解决这事
We can fix this.
我们只要让他的心腹复原
We just make his right-hand man right again,
这个罗德里克
this Roderick fellow,
也许哈特利会同意做个交换
and then maybe Hartley will agree to a little quid pro quo.
我有个想法
I have a theory.
我收到了你的短信  你还好吗
I got your text. Are you okay?
-是伤口开始恶化了吗  -拉尔夫  我没事
- Is the wound getting worse? - Ralph, I'm fine.
作为一个胸口有着慢性光子弹分裂的人来说
As fine as anyone with a chronic light bullet avulsion
我可是好的很
can be in their chest, but...
这补丁暂时让我稳定下来了
This patch is keeping me stable for now.
-那这紧急情况是什么  -回报
- Then what's the emergency? - Payback.
我只是想说声谢谢
I just wanted to say thank you
为你这一年为我所做的所有事
for everything you've done for me this year--
带我去参加艺术展览
for taking me to an art show
还教会我如果接触到
and teaching me how to get in touch with emotions
我都不知道存在的情感
I didn't even know I had.
生活导师就是干这个的
Hey, that's what life coaches are for.
我知道我还有很长的路要走
Well, I know I've still got a long way to go,
但是我很快就要离开了
but I'm leaving soon,
所以我们可能要半途而废了
so we might not be able to finish this.
你复原是我们现在的首要任务
You getting better is our number-one priority.
而且你妈妈对冰很有研究
And your mom is the expert on all things ice,
所以她会给你补好那个伤口的
so she'll patch up that wound of yours,
然后我们可以接着继续下去
and then we can pick up where we left off.
我可能会离开很长时间
I could be gone for a long time.
好吧
Okay.
但你会回来的  对吧
But you are coming back, right?
拉尔夫  还是忘了这事吧
Look, Ralph, forget it.
我只是想和老朋友道个别
I-I just--I wanted to say good-bye to an old friend.
你看
Look...
朋友之间会说“走好”  或是"下回见"
Friends say "So long" Or--or "Until we meet again."
他们不会真的道别
They--they don't really say good-bye.
所以为什么不告诉我你真正的烦恼
So why don't you just tell me what's really bothering you?
我没事
I'm fine.
别老想着闻出谜题什么的
Stop trying to smell a mystery or whatever.
太晚了
Too late.
唐豪瑟的科技
The Tannhauser tech--
是唯一能修复你的东西
it's the only stuff that can fix you,
但你不是真的想去  对吗
but you don't really want to go, do you?
别管了
Just drop it.
不是因为那技术  对不对
It's not the tech, is it?
是后面的人
It's the person behind it.
冰霜  你为什么不想见卡拉
Frost, why don't you want to see Carla?
因为她不是我的妈妈
Because she's not my mom, okay?
她是凯特琳的
She's Caity's.
-你不是这个意思  -不  我是的
- You don't really mean that. - Yeah, I do.
卡拉又不认识我
Carla doesn't know me.
这么些年来  就只是她和凯特琳
After all these years, it's just been her and Caity.
你也是她的女儿
Hey, you're her daughter, too.
我是她女儿性格的阴暗面
I am the cold, dark part of her daughter
她平常要忍受的
that she tolerates.
如果你说的是真的话
If that were even true,
我为什么会坐在这里替你担心
why would I be sitting here worried about you?
因为你是个好人  拉尔夫
Cause you're a good guy, Ralph.
你是闪电小队同等的一员
And you're an equal member of Team Flash,
就像凯特琳一样
just like Caitlin.
而且你也同等重要
And you are just as important.
如果这你都看不出来的话
And if you can't see that for yourself...
或许你说的是对的
Then maybe you're right.
或许你真的还有很长的路要走
Maybe you do have a long way to go.
你好啊  闪电侠
Hello, Flash.
我早就听到你过来了
I heard you coming from a mile away.
哈特利  我知道到底发生什么了
Hartley, I know what happened now.
我很抱歉
And I'm sorry.
你的速度出什么问题了
Is something wrong with your speed?
听着  我
Look, I'm--
我想改善我们两个的关系
I'm trying to make things right with you.
-现在知道道歉了  -我觉得我能帮罗德里克
- Now you're sorry? - I think I can help Roderick.
你都知道关于罗德里克的什么
What do you know about Roderick?
我知道他现在的情况是我的错
I know his condition's my fault,
但是如果你给我机会我认为我可以帮到他
but I think I can fix it if you'll give me the chance.
还有什么
And?
如果你愿意的话  我需要你的帮忙
And if you're willing, I could use your help.
-有一个新的极速者  -又开始了
- There's a new speedster. - Hmm, here we go.
他对这个城市构成巨大的威胁  哈特利
He's a threat to the whole city, Hartley.
他用声波
He's using sound waves.
你是我们知道的唯一一个能阻止他的人
You're the only person we know that can stop him.
-人命...  -我不在乎
- Lives-- - I don't care.
我发誓我想要帮助罗德里克
I swear I want to help Roderick.
-但是你帮不上  -让我试一下
- Well, you can't. - Let me try.
我说过了你帮不到他
I said you can't help him.
还没明白吗  没人能帮他
Don't you get it? No one can.
我以为我能稳定他的分子
I thought I could stabilize his molecules
用我的声波  但是
with my sonics, but...
我还不够强大
I wasn't strong enough.
所以你把他送去了水星实验室
So you sent him to Mercury Labs.
我们觉得我们能帮到他  让我们给你看一下
We think we can help him. Let us show you.
你说的我们都是谁
Who is this "We" And "Us"?
哈里森·威尔斯
Harrison Wells.
其实是纳什·威尔斯
Nash Wells, actually.
哈里森·威尔斯的二重身
Harrison Wells is my doppelganger.
-你的二重身  -怎么解释呢
- Your doppelganger? - How to explain?
之前有一个大事件我们叫危机  然后
Okay, so there was this big event we call the Crisis, and--
-他们两个是双胞胎  -他是我双胞胎
- He's his twin. - He's my twin.
福成双对
Huh, twice blessed.
我们认为真的有一种办法
We think that there may actually be a way
能帮到罗德里克
to help Roderick.
我以前见到过这种分子离体
I've seen this kind of molecular disembodiment before,
而且  听我细说
and--all right, bear with me--
我认为如果我们把集中光能
I think that if we combine concentrated light energy
和一个有高热能传导的惰性气体结合
with an inert gas with high thermal conductivity,
或许能减缓罗德里克的分子
it may actually slow down Roderick's molecules
然后他的身体就回来了
and get him his body back.
所以就是将光和氦气组合起来
So basically combine light with helium.
我是这屋里最聪明的人  我知道
I'm the smartest guy in the room--I get it.
好吧
Fine.
如果你救好了罗德里克  或许我会帮你们
You fix Roderick, and maybe I'll help you.
卡米拉
Kamilla?
等一下  你在干什么  是我  爱瑞丝
Wait, what are you doing? It's me, Iris.
是你让我来这的
You're the one who sent me here.
不是  无论她是谁  那个人不是我
No, whoever she was, that was not me.
我发誓
I swear.
那告诉我只有真的爱瑞丝才会知道的事
Then tell me something only the real Iris would know.
西斯科是你的一生所爱
Cisco is the love of your life.
你从见到他的那刻就知道
And you knew it from the moment you met him...
就是你在小猫酒吧调酒的时候
when you were bartending at the Liquid Kitty.
他是你认识的最有才华的人
He is the most brilliant man that you know,
他总会逗你笑
and he always makes you laugh.
只有你会允许穿丘巴卡运动衫
You are the only person allowed to wear his Chewbacca T-shirt,
那件运动衫是他十四岁时他父母送他的
the one that his parents gave him when he was 14 years old.
真的是你
It's you.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
在你  或者那个像你的人
After you-- or whoever looked like you--
用镜像枪朝我开枪之后
shot me with that mirror gun,
我醒过来就自己一个人在这
I just woke up here totally alone.
你没看到过伊娃
You never saw Eva?
伊娃·麦克洛奇  卡夫的妻子
Eva McCulloch--Carver's wife.
她还活着吗  她在这吗
She's alive? She's--she's here?
她是这些事件背后的超能力者
She's the meta behind all of this,
现在她逃到我们的世界去了
and--and now she's escaped into our world.
我们得回去
Then we have to get back.
我把镜像枪送过来的东西集中起来
I gathered all the items that the mirror gun sent here.
一直分析它们来寻找线索
I've been analyzing them for clues,
但当我看屏幕的时候
but the data keeps getting all wonky
数据总是晃动
when I try to see the screen.
你还好吗
Hey, are you okay?
不  我不好
No. No, I'm not.
但你还好
But you are.
你还没有感染神经不协调症
The neural dissonance hasn't affected you yet.
正是这一状况影响了我们的大脑
It's this condition that affects our minds
在这  这个镜像宇宙中
in this, uh-- this Mirrorverse.
这就解释了屏幕的问题
That explains the screens.
当我看得太久  就会头疼
When I look at them too long, I get a headache.
是的  这就是我开始时的症状
Yeah, that's how it started for me, too,
当看伊娃的电脑时
with Eva's computers.
所有事情都破碎断裂了
Everything was broken and--and fractured, but...
但现在我能读取它们
now--now I can read them.
你能帮我们出去
You can help us get out of here.
你知道  我不能
Ah, you know, I-I can't.
事实很伤人  事实很伤人
Shh. The truth hurts. The truth hurts.
我们不应该在这  我们不应该在这
We--we--we shouldn't be here. We should not be here.
我不应该在这
I should not be here.
没多大改变嘛
Not much has changed.
尖端科研实验室
Ugh, S.T.A.R. Labs--
依旧有一堆平庸的工程师
still keeping mediocre engineers around, I see.
我们必须和这个蠢货一起工作吗
Do we have to work with this douchebag?
我听说了  你俩讨厌对方
Look, I've heard that you two hate each other,
但我们先集中注意力吧
but let's just focus.
几个月前
A few months ago,
我推测可能有一种机械方式
I theorized there might be a mechanical way
能打开通往不同维度的缺口
to open a breach to an alternate dimension.
看起来像一台聚焦亚原子共振的机器
Looks like an engine for focusing subatomic vibrations,
或者就像你说的  震波
or as you would say, "Vibes."
拜托  我老早就看出来了
Oh, please. I figured that out ages ago.
头发 直接露馅了  拉蒙
The hair? Dead giveaway, Ramon.
你也是  闪电侠
You too, Flash.
在整个国家只有三处设施
There's only three facilities in the state
能够用那么前沿的科技来构建一套战服
that could build a suit with that much bleeding-edge tech.
但只有一处有足够聪明的人
But only one of them had someone brilliant enough
可以构建它
to build it.
-谢谢  -哈里森·威尔斯
- Thanks. - Harrison Wells.
开始了
There it is.
我不明白的是为什么你需要机器
What I don't get is why you need a machine
你明明可以用你的震波
when you could just use your damn vibes.
除非你不能再震波了
Unless you can't vibe anymore.
天呐  你失去你的超能力了
Ooh, ouch. You lost your meta-mojo.
你可以尝试成为一名咖啡师
Oh, well, you could try being a barista maybe.
我是自愿放弃我的超能力的
I gave up my powers by choice.
我这么做
You know, I'm making this
是为了救我最爱的人
so that I can save the person I love the most.
但我不指望你理解  哈特利
But I wouldn't expect you to understand that, Hartley.
你最爱的人是你自己
The person you love the most is yourself.
当你准备好工作  来找我
Come find me when you're ready to work.
塞西尔刚从水星实验室带回罗德里克
Cecile just got Roderick back from Mercury Labs.
他来了
He's here.
我需要你帮这个忙
Here's what I need from you.
我需要你向接收导管中
I need you to direct a concentrated UV blast
发射高浓度紫外线
into the reception conduit.
我会向这个密闭装置中释放氦气
Now, this containment unit-- I am going to release helium into it,
这两种物质在里面相撞后
and when those two things collide, pop.
应该可以让罗德里克的分子恢复人类形态
It should lock Roderick's molecules back into human form.
准备好了吗  数到三
Ready? We'll go on three.
一  二
One... two...
三
three.
起作用了
It's working.
不  等等  停下
No, no, wait. Stop.
威尔斯  够了
Wells, enough.
快停下  你伤到他了
Stop, you're hurting him!
纳什
Nash.
哈特利  我很抱歉  但我们可以试试
Hartley, I'm sorry, but we can try--
我相信你真是太蠢了
I was stupid for trusting you.
别再要求我做任何事
Don't ask me for anything, ever.
我的世界消失了
My world is over.
希望你们的也被毁掉
I hope yours burns.
把你的速度给我  否则你的城市会付出代价
Give me your velocity, or your city pays.
你有一个小时
You have one hour.
你的速度还不够快  无法阻止我
You're not fast enough to stop me.
你们都无法阻止
None of you are.
死亡将会降临你的城市  闪电侠
Death will rain down on your city, Flash,
除非你把我想要的给我
unless you give me what I want.
希望你做出明智的选择
Choose wisely.
我觉得这些公式
I don't think these equations
对治好罗德里克帮助不大
are gonna help fix Roderick that much.
再说  我们只是需要更强效的粘合剂
Plus, we simply need a better bonding agent.
你去解决那个问题
You do that.
我正在研究人造神速力
I'm working on the Artificial Speed Force right now.
纳什  你在干什么
Nash! Hey, Nash, what the hell?
我已经研究一天了
I've been working on these all day.
你这是浪费时间  为什么
You're wasting time. Why?
你用不着告诉我  我们不熟
You don't have to tell me. We don't know each other.
你可以和乔还有爱瑞丝说
You could talk to Joe and Iris.
但是他们不在  这是谁的错
But they're not here. Whose fault is that?
-这都是谁的错  -都是我的错  好吗
- Whose fault is that? - It's mine, all right?
你就是想让我承认这一点吗
Is that what you want me to say?
我本该领导这支队伍
I'm supposed to lead this team.
但是现在  我都不知道应该对他们说什么
Now, I- I don't even know what to tell them.
在我失去玛雅时
When I lost Maya...
每一天我都想说
every day since then, I wanted to say,
我很抱歉  都是我的错
"Hey, listen, I'm sorry. It was my fault."
但是她不在了
But she's gone.
我变成遭弃者时
When I was Pariah
我看着我的失误摧毁了多元宇宙
and I watched my mistake burn down the Multiverse,
我想对那些人说  对不起
I wanted to tell those people, "I'm sorry,"
但是他们都不在了  已经无法挽回
but they were gone, and it was over.
但对你来说一切还没有结束
And this is not over for you.
你能够从中找到办法
You can find your way out of this.
你只需要相信自己
All you have to do is trust yourself.
我要怎么相信自己
How am I supposed to do that?
我和一个冒充者生活了五个星期
I just lived with an impostor for five weeks.
你要原谅自己
You forgive yourself.
你教会了我这样做
You showed me that.
现在你要为了自己做到这一点
Now it's time for you to do it for you.
如果你做不到的话
And you know what? If you can't...
就当是为了爱瑞丝
do it for Iris.
我太想她了
I just miss her so much.
她不在这里  感觉就像
Without her here, it feels like...
我知道哈特利的世界为什么消失了
I know why Hartley's world is over.
谢谢你  纳什
Thank you, Nash.
我知道你很难过  我理解
Look, I know you're hurting. I do.
血怒的怪物袭击时  我和卡米拉在一起
But I was with Kamilla when Bloodwork's monsters attacked,
你要相信  不论她在哪里
and-- and you got to trust me that no matter where she is,
你的女朋友知道怎样保护自己
your girl knows how to take care of herself.
没错  我知道
Yeah. Yeah, I know. I know.
只是
It's just...
卡米拉在的时候
When Kamilla's around,
我想向她展示我很强大
I want to show her I'm strong.
我想相信自己的决定是对的
I want to believe I'm making the right decisions.
她给了我所需要的自信  但她...
She gives me the confidence I need, but she's...
她不在了
She's not here.
而我满脑子想的都是我曾是个英雄
And all I can think about is the hero I used to be.
他充满活力
He was just full of life,
他敢于去做不可能的事
and he wasn't afraid to do the impossible.
他是...
He was...
他是震波  你知道吗
He was Vibe, you know?
他知道所有问题的答案
He had all the answers.
有时他自己就是答案
Sometimes he was the answer.
如果卡米拉不在这里而震波也消失了
If Kamilla's not here and Vibe is gone...
如果...
what if--
如果你不知道所有问题的答案呢
What if you don't have all the answers
如果你做的决定是错的呢
and you're making the wrong decisions?
西斯科  卡米拉爱的不是你的超能力
Cisco, Kamilla did not fall in love with your powers.
她爱的是你
She fell in love with you...
你
you...
还有你那强大的大脑
and that big, beautiful brain of yours.
西斯科·拉蒙不再是震波了
Boo-hoo, Cisco Ramon isn't Vibe anymore.
你知道他现在是什么人吗
You know what he is?
他是位非常杰出的工程师
He is a damn brilliant engineer
他绝不会放弃去做不可能的事
who has never backed down from doing the impossible before.
你现在要放弃吗
You gonna start now?
不  女士
No, ma'am.
你没事吧
You okay?
我一直任由伊娃操纵我
I let Eva manipulate me all this time,
现在神经失调越来越严重了
and now the neural dissonance is getting worse.
我怎么能让这种事发生
How did I let that happen?
作为记者  我的技能就是看到真相
My skill as a reporter is being able to see the truth,
但伊娃向我证明了我不能相信自己的直觉
but Eva proved to me that I can't trust my instincts
或相信我自己
or...myself.
你不是唯一被她骗的人
You weren't the only one she tricked.
你的复制品骗了我  大家  甚至巴里
Your duplicate tricked me, everyone--even Barry.
别因为自己不完美而自责
Don't beat yourself up for not being perfect.
伊娃当然想让你
Of course Eva would want you
把自己的优点当成缺点
to see your strength as a weakness.
她就是这样把你困住的
That's how she's kept you trapped.
但如果你想逃走
But if you want to escape,
就必须再次相信自己
you have to trust yourself again.
我相信你
I do.
所以
So...
我们从何入手
where do we start?
伊娃还创造了另一个复制品  辛格局长
There is one other duplicate that Eva created--Chief Singh.
我们得找到他
We should find him.
我们如果要回家  就都得回家
If we're gonna go home, we're all going home...
一起
together.
走开
Get out.
我知道你为什么这么沮丧
I know why you're so upset.
你对我一无所知
You don't know anything about me.
我知道因为自己的错痛失所爱的人
I know what it's like to be responsible
是什么感觉
for losing the person I love.
罗德里克...
Roderick...
他不只是职业杀手  对吗
he's not just another hired gun, is he?
他是我的男友
He's my boyfriend...
我一生的挚爱
The love of my life.
我和你对战时让他身处战火之中
I put him in the line of fire when I fought you,
意味着他遭受的一切都是我的错
meaning that what happened to him is my fault.
这不是你一个人的错
You're not the only one to blame.
我发射了闪电  记得吗
I threw the lightning, remember?
我给了他武器  所以你才要自卫
I gave him the weapon that made you defend yourself.
然后我却救不了他
And then when I couldn't help him...
你给了他所需要的帮助
You got him the help he needed.
他在水星实验室比跟我在一起好
He was better off at Mercury Labs than with me.
我毫无用处
I was useless.
有人刚刚提醒了我
Someone just reminded me that...
如果我们找不到前进的力量并原谅自己
we're no good to the people that we love
就会对我们所爱的人
if we can't find the strength to move forward
毫无益处
and forgive ourselves.
谢谢  奥普拉女士
Thanks, Oprah.
我们在铁山监狱有大麻烦了
Hey, we got a big problem at Iron Heights.
你可以留在这
You can stay here.
也可以成为那个罗德里克爱上的人
Or you can be the person that Roderick fell in love with.
你自己决定
It's your call.
卫星刚刚感应到
The satellites just picked up
超能力片区中巨大的能量激增
a massive energy surge in the Meta-Wing.
消失了
It's gone.
等等  跟进一下视频  里面发生了什么
Wait, get a video feed. What happened in there?
我正在试
I'm trying.
糟糕
Oh, crap.
直到现在我们抓到的所有神速
Every Godspeed we caught till now--
他取走了他们的速度
He took all their speed.
听着  你有一分钟  闪电侠
Record this. You have one minute, Flash.
在那之后  每一分钟
After that, someone dies
突发新闻
市民被扣为人质
就会死一人  直到你交出属于我的东西
every 60 seconds until you surrender what's mine.
我得去阻止他
I have to stop him.
-等等  等等  巴里  -怎么了
- Wait, wait, Barry. - What?
我知道你想去
Look, I know you want to do this,
但是你没多少速度了  好吗
but you don't have a lot of speed, okay?
我们得通知中城警局或天眼会  任何能...
We need to call CCPD, or A.R.G.U.S., anyone who can--
神速是我的责任
Godspeed is my responsibility.
-我必须去面对他  -巴里  你不必
- I have to face him. - Barry, you don't--
我还剩下足够的速度去做这件事
I have enough speed left to do this.
就算我没有  我也得去试试
Even if I don't, I have to try.
我必须去试试
I have to try.
每一分钟就会死一人
Someone dies every 60 seconds
直到你交出属于我的东西
until you surrender what's mine.
神速是我的责任
Godspeed is my responsibility.
我必须去面对他  我必须去试试
I have to face him. I have to try.
我还剩下足够的速度去做这件事
I have enough speed left to do this.
-有人会死  有人会死  -我必须去试试
- Someone dies. Someone dies. - I have to try.
我必须去试试  我必须去试试  我必须去试试
I have to try. I have to try. I have to try.
时间到了  闪电侠
Time's up, Flash.
你是来把我的东西给我吗
Have you come to give me what's mine?
你得先抓到我
You have to catch me first.
他的速度达到5马赫  他跑的比你快
He's running at Mach 5. He's moving faster than you.
但是我比他更了解这个城市
But I know this city better than him.
巴里
Barry!
你真可悲
You are pathetic.
你配不上你得到的速度
You don't deserve the speed you were given.
我们才配
We do!
我以为你不来了
I didn't think you were coming.
我救你不是为了聊天
I didn't save you so we could chat.
那是你的后援  没用的
That's your backup? It won't help.
哈特利  我不能阻止神速  他太强大了
Hartley, I can't stop Godspeed. He's too powerful.
天啊  你是有多蠢
God, how thick are you?
当你投掷的闪电与他的武器的振动力碰撞时
Roderick got hurt when the lightning you threw collided
罗德里克受伤了
with the vibrational force of his weapon.
结果就是一个热爆冲击波
The result was a thermogenic blast capable
使他在分子水平上不稳定
of rendering him unstable at a molecular level.
-复制那个力量  -神速就玩完了
- Just duplicate that force... - And Godspeed's toast.
-没错  猜对了  -闪电侠
- Bingo bango. - Flash!
现在你会感受到速度真正的力量
Now you'll feel the real power of speed!
-你准备好了吗  -开始吧
- You ready? - Let's do it.
他要去哪里
Where is he going?
巴里  你跑反了
Barry, you're going the wrong way.
等一下
Wait for it.
现在  闪电侠
Now, Flash!
-他们把射线交互了  -射线交互
- They crossed streams. - Crossed streams.
哈特利  谢谢你随我一起来了
Hartley, thanks for coming after me.
不客气
Yeah, don't mention it.
你赢了另一场和速度怪人的战斗
You won another battle against some speed freak,
而我失去了所有
and I lost everything.
我保证我们会想出办法的
I promise we'll figure something out.
我还没看见过这个
Okay, I haven't seen that one before.
这是神速的血吗
Is that Godspeed's blood?
卫星读数显示
Satellite readings indicate
这可能是某种生物电解质分泌物
it could be some kind of biogenic electrolyte secretion.
-这是带电声波  -带电声波
- It's charged sound. - Charged sound.
小伙子们
Oh, boys...
我想我们真的找到了我们一直在找的解决办法
I do believe we found the solution we're looking for.
解决办法是什么
How does it work?
普通的声波需要传播介质才能够传播
Normal sound waves need to have a transmission medium
但带电声波可以自行构建传播介质
to move through, but charged sound builds its own.
普通的声波可以暂时重新连上分子键
Normal sound can temporarily reattach molecular bonds.
但带电声波可以永久性地连接分子键
Charged sound can permanently attach them.
就像是一个永久性的粘结剂
It's like a permanent bonding agent.
哈特利  这一定能让罗德里克恢复正常
Hartley, this will stabilize Roderick.
要是你伤害到他  我一定不会让你好受
If you hurt him, I'll hurt you.
-准备好了吗  -准备好了
- Ready? - Ready.
哈特利
Hartley.
-哈特利  -我在这
- Hartley. - I'm here.
我还以为我失去你了
I thought I lost you.
得了吧  你明知道我没那么容易甩掉的
Come on, you know I'm harder to get rid of than that.
那  到底发生了什么
So, uh, what happened?
我最后记得的事是  我们在大坝那里
Last thing I remember, we were at the dam,
还有闪电侠  他...
and the Flash, he, um...
是他帮忙治好你的
He helped bring you back.
我们让你们俩单独待一会
We'll give you guys some space.
虽然我很高兴我们让幸福情侣重聚了
I'm glad we reunited the happy couple,
不过我还是要说
but I have to say--
终于能摆脱神速真是让我太解脱了
I am super relieved to finally get rid of Godspeed.
而且这个能说话  所以现在我们知道
And this one talks, so now we know
我们关进牢的是真正的奥古斯特·哈特
we got the real August Hart behind bars.
那并不是真的神速
That's not the real Godspeed.
当他被关在超能力元电阻尼牢房里的时候
Once he was placed in a meta-dampening cell,
我以闪电侠的身份问过他
I questioned him as the Flash,
当时他只能说
and all he could say was,
"派我来的人想获得无限的速度"
"The one who sent me wants infinite velocity."
你之前和神速打的时候  他说过
When you were fighting Godspeed, he said,
"我们值得拥有你的速度"
"We deserve your speed."
"我们"是指谁
Who's "We"?
"我们"是否包含派他来的那个人
Does "We" include the one who sent him?
-他没法告诉我  -因为他不再说话
- He couldn't tell me. - Because he stopped talking.
然后就开始像一个坏了的调制解调器一样鸣叫
And started chirping like a broken modem...
跟其他那些一样
just like the rest of them.
那个...
So...
我  是来道歉的
I, uh, came to apologize.
你窍门进来的  我的前门是锁上了的
So you broke in? My front door is locked.
我可能是从门框下溜进来的
I may have, uh, slipped under the doorframe,
不夸张
uh, literally.
所以其实我应该有两件事要向你道歉
So I guess I actually have two things to apologize for.
听我说...
Um, listen...
我之前不应该说得那么重
I shouldn't have been so harsh.
没事  你说得对
It's okay. You were right.
-我确实还有很长的路要去走  -不  不需要了
- I have a long way to go. - No, you don't.
德比证书
冰霜
"德比证书"
A "Dib-ploma"?
恭喜你已经从生活导师学校毕业了
Congratulations on graduating life-coach school.
-拉尔夫  这太扯了  -你知道什么才真扯吗
- Ralph, this is ridiculous. - You know what's ridiculous?
你居然认为你自己不如凯特琳重要
You thinking that you're not as important as Caitlin.
而且害怕见家长  这可是很正常的
And being intimidated by a parent, that--that's normal.
冰霜  我爸抛下我和我妈的时候我只有十岁
Frost, I was ten when my dad walked out on Mom and me.
你觉得我有一天没有
You don't think a day goes by where I'm not...
害怕着他会突然
absolutely terrified that he's gonna show up
出现在我们前吗
at my front door?
他抛下了你们  他是个混蛋
He walked out on you guys. He's a jerk.
没错
Yeah.
但我内心有一部分仍然想要见到他
And a part of me still wants to see him.
我想我担心卡拉
I guess I'm afraid Carla
可能真的想要了解我  然后...
might actually want to get to know me, and then...
她就会了解我的真实身份
she'll see me for who I really am.
对我来说这理由可真够讽刺的
That is the ironic part to me.
因为冰霜  你是一个非常棒的人
'Cause, Frosty, you are one awesome human being.
你害怕只是因为怕卡拉会排斥你
You were just afraid that Carla was gonna reject you,
所以你就先疏远了她
so you rejected her first.
不会再这样了
Not anymore.
这就是你已经准备好毕业的表现
And that is why you're ready to graduate.
天哪  我真是一名优秀的人生导师
Damn, I really am one hell of a life coach.
是的  没错
Yeah, you are.
我都不知道该怎么谢谢你
I don't know how to thank you.
当我们失去彼此的时候
I--we lost everything
我们就失去了一切
when we lost each other...
失去了希望
even hope.
谢谢你没有放弃我们
Thank you for not giving up.
你让我们重新团聚
You gave us back us.
我们两个都欠你人情
I owe you. We both do.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
以后尽量别去钻石店了
Just maybe stay out of diamond stores for a while.
这可不一定
No promises.
能让我们单独说话吗
Hey, will you give us a second?
行
Yeah.
好了
Okay, look, um...
你知道我不太喜欢和别人拥抱
You know I'm not exactly the "Let's hug it out" type,
我要告诉你
so I'll just say this-- -
你为我找回了我的世界
You gave me my world back.
你也一定会找回自己的世界
You'll get your world back, too.
但你需要做的不只是原谅自己
But you have to do more than just forgive yourself.
你要相信你的世界可以改变
You have to believe that your world can change.
我以前忘了这些
That's the part I'd forgotten.
谢谢你提醒我
Thanks for reminding me.
我们在这一年都失去了很多
We've all lost so much this year...
我们的能力  我们的爱情
our power, our love,
我们的家人
our family.
有时候  我们仿佛已经输的一无所有
At times, it's even felt like there's nothing left to lose,
我们生命中所有重要的事都被夺走
like everything that matters has already been taken
我们的生活变得空虚
and our lives are empty...
空洞
hollow inside.
有些东西是无法被夺走的
Some things can't be taken.
看看这里的大家
Look around this room.
我们还有对彼此的信任
We still have our faith in each other
为了我们所爱的人战斗的意志
and our will to fight for those we love.
我们永远不会失去这些
This is what we'll never lose.
伊娃·麦克洛奇从未与我们正面交锋
Eva McCulloch has never faced us head-on.
而我们要主动出击
And that's about to change.
我们要找到她
We're gonna find her...
打败她
beat her...
救回所有人
and get back everyone.
说得好
Amen to that.
只要你告诉我去哪里
You just tell me where to stretch.
炸掉哪里
And blast.
听起来很暴力  算我一个
Sounds violent. I'm in.
我有个主意
I have an idea...
把他们从镜像宇宙救出来的办法
a way to get our people out of the Mirrorverse.
我们需要一个无损耗的
We need a lossless,
自给自足的无限能量源
self-sustaining source of perpetual energy.
听起来像是科学里的圣杯
Sounds like you're talking about the holy grail of science--
永动机
a perpetual-motion machine.
对
That's right.
哈特利有过一些研究
Hartley had some ideas.
我认为我们真的能造出来
I think we can actually build one.
我们只差一个组件
We're just missing one component,
多亏了我的旅行
and thanks to my travels,
我知道去哪能找到它
I know exactly where to find it...
亚特兰蒂斯
Atlantis.
危机可算有些好的影响了
Finally, Crisis pays off in a good way for once.
我知道时间很紧  别担心
I know time is crucial, but don't worry.
-我去去就回  -我能去吗
- I'll hurry back. - Can I come?
如果你不介意的话  我希望你留下
Actually, if you don't mind, I'd like for you to stay.
闪电侠小队需要尽可能多的人手
Team Flash needs as many hands on deck as possible.
我们开始吧
Now let's get to work.
麦克洛奇科技公司
我要来找你了  约瑟夫
I'm coming for you, Joseph.